Yuehan (Jenny) Zhang

615 N Wolfe St · Baltimore, MD 21205 · yuehan@jhu.edu · http://www.yhzhang.me/

PROFILE

PhD candidate in Cancer Epidemiology and MHS student in Biostatistics experienced in conducting population health research studies. Researcher with a strong interest in integrating epidemiologic, molecular, and big data perspectives into a deeper understanding of cancer development and for translation into cancer prevention.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Epidemiology (Cancer Epidemiology)	Sept. 2019-Present	
Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health (JHSPH), Baltimore, MD	Advisor: Dr. Gypsyamber D'Souza	
Master of Health Science in Biostatistics	Sept. 2020-Present	
JHSPH, Baltimore, MD	Advisor: Dr. Ni Zhao	
Master of Science in Epidemiology (General Epidemiology and Methodology)	May 2015	
JHSPH, Baltimore, MD (Grade: 4.0/4.0)	Advisor: Dr. Elizabeth Golub	

Certificate: Pharmacoepidemiology and Drug Safety

Bachelor of Science in Biotechnology

July 2013

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China (Grade: 3.8/4.0)

HONORS AND AWARDS

Leon Gordis Teaching Assistantship in Epidemiology Methods, JHSPH	2020-2021
Delta Omega Scholarship Award (Applied Research), JHSPH	May 2020
Harvey M. Meyerhoff Fellowship in Cancer Prevention, JHSPH	2019-2010
Delta Omega Public Health Honor Society, Alpha Chapter	May 2015
AAAS/Science Program for Excellence in Science, American Association for the Advancement of Science	May 2015
Dorothy and Arthur Samet Student Support Fund in Epidemiology, JHSPH	May 2015
Master's Tuition Scholarship, JHSPH	Sept. 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant: Epidemiologic Methods course sequence (four courses)

Sept 2020-Present

Department of Epidemiology, JHSPH

- Lead weekly large group discussions of learning exercises (~65 students)
- Field questions from students during office hours and on a web-based platform used for the course

Research Data Analyst March 2020-Present

Department of Epidemiology, JHSPH

Supervisors: Drs. Lorraine Dean, Sabina Haberlen

- Examine racial disparities in healthcare spending and associations with neighborhood characteristics using 2016 Medical Expenditure Panel Survey data
- Assess the effect of syndemic factors on psychosocial health in the COVID-19 pandemic using the MACS and WIHS data

Senior Statistical Analyst

Statistical Analyst

July 2018-June 2019

Supervisor: Dr. Daniel Polsky

Supervisor: Dr. Amber D'Souza

Division of General Internal Medicine, University of Pennsylvania

June 2016-July 2018

Division of General Internal Medicine, Chrycisty of Lennsylvania

Constructed measures of provider network characteristics on the ACA Marketplaces from 2016-2018
Examined driving time access to primary care physicians and psychiatrists by rurality using generalized linear regression

Research Data Analyst

June 2015-June 2016

Department of Epidemiology, JHSPH

Assessed longitudinal trends of HPV oncogenic antibodies after treatment of HPV-driven oropharyngeal cancer (HPV-OPC) and examined whether antibody levels at diagnosis predicted risk of cancer recurrence

Yuehan (Jenny) Zhang

615 N Wolfe St · Baltimore, MD 21205 · yuehan@jhu.edu · http://www.yhzhang.me/

• Constructed Kaplan-Meier curves and Cox proportional hazards models to estimate survival differences among oropharyngeal and nonoropharyngeal cancer patients by tumor HPV status, gender, and race/ethnicity

Research Assistant June 2014-May 2015

Department of Epidemiology, JHSPH

Supervisor: Dr. Amber D'Souza

- Conducted survival analysis to investigate the natural history of oral HPV infection among a cohort of young adults
- Performed cross-sectional analysis to assess patient psychosocial experiences and knowledge of oral HPV infection during and after treatment of HPV-OPC

Research Assistant July-Nov. 2014

Women's Interagency HIV Study (WIHS) Data Management and Analysis Center

Supervisor: Dr. Elizabeth Golub

- Assessed exchangeability in a large multicenter cohort study by reviewing eligibility criteria over four enrollment waves
- Estimated HIV incidence rate over the entire WIHS study period and summarized participants characteristics at enrollment

Teaching Assistant June-July 2014

Principles of Epidemiology (340.601.11)

Instructor: Dr. Lechaim Naggan

Graduate Summer Institute of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, JHSPH

- Led discussions on selected public health topics (50 students) and held weekly office hours to answer students' questions
- Member of instructor and teaching assistant team meeting weekly to coordinate teaching

PUBLICATIONS

Drake C, Jarlenski M, **Zhang Y**, Polsky D. Market Share of US Catholic Hospitals and Associated Geographic Network Access to Reproductive Health Services. JAMA Network Open. 2020 Jan 3;3(1):e1920053-.

Dean LT, Ransome Y, Frasso-Jaramillo L, Moss SL, **Zhang Y**, Ashing K, Denis GV, Frick KD, Visvanathan K, Schmitz KH. Drivers of cost differences between US breast cancer survivors with or without lymphedema. Journal of Cancer Survivorship. 2019 Oct 1;13(5):804-14.

Drake C, **Zhang Y**, Chaiyachati KH, Polsky D. The limitations of poor broadband internet access for telemedicine use in rural America: an observational study. Annals of internal medicine. 2019 Sep 3;171(5):382-4.

Dean LT, Moss SL, Ransome Y, Frasso-Jaramillo L, **Zhang Y**, Visvanathan K, et al. "It still affects our economic situation": long-term economic burden of breast cancer and lymphedema. Supportive Care in Cancer. 2018 Aug 18.doi: 10.1007/s00520-018-4418-4

Dean LT, Schmitz KH, Frick KD, Nicholas LH, **Zhang Y**, Subramanian SV, et al. Consumer credit as a novel marker for economic burden and health after cancer in a diverse population of breast cancer survivors in the USA. Journal of Cancer Survivorship. 2018 Jun 1;12(3):306-15.

Rettig EM, Fakhry C, Hales RK, Kisuule F, Quon H, Kiess AP, Yin LX, **Zhang Y**, Blackford AL, Drummond MB, Gourin CG. Pilot randomized controlled trial of a comprehensive smoking cessation intervention for patients with upper aerodigestive cancer undergoing radiotherapy. Head & neck. 2018 Jul;40(7):1534-47.

Yin LX, D'Souza G, Westra WH, Wang SJ, van Zante A, **Zhang Y**, et al. Prognostic factors for human papillomavirus—positive and negative oropharyngeal carcinomas. The Laryngoscope. 2018 Mar 14;128(8):E288-E296.

Zhang Y, Wilson TE, Adedimeji A, Merenstein D, Milam J, Cohen J, et al. The impact of substance use on adherence to antiretroviral therapy among HIV-infected women in the United States. AIDS and Behavior. 2018 Mar 1;22(3):896-908.

Zhu JM, **Zhang Y**, Wu B, Polsky D. Association between number of insurers and premium rates in the Affordable Care Act marketplace. JAMA Internal Medicine. 2017 Nov 1;177(11):1684-6.

Zhu JM, **Zhang Y**, Polsky D. Networks in ACA marketplaces are narrower for mental health care than for primary care. Health Affairs. 2017 Sep 1;36(9):1624-31.

Fakhry C, Westra WH, Wang SJ, van Zante A, **Zhang Y**, Rettig E, et al. The prognostic role of sex, race, and human papillomavirus in oropharyngeal and nonoropharyngeal head and neck squamous cell cancer. Cancer. 2017 May 1;123(9):1566-75.

Yuehan (Jenny) Zhang

615 N Wolfe St · Baltimore, MD 21205 · yuehan@jhu.edu · http://www.yhzhang.me/

Zhang Y, Waterboer T, Haddad RI, Miles BA, Wentz A, Gross ND, et al. Human papillomavirus (HPV) 16 antibodies at diagnosis of HPV-related oropharyngeal cancer and antibody trajectories after treatment. Oral Oncology. 2017 Apr 1;67:77-82.

D'Souza G, **Zhang Y**, Merritt S, Gold D, Robbins HA, Buckman V, et al. Patient experience and anxiety during and after treatment for an HPV-related oropharyngeal cancer. Oral Oncology. 2016 Sep 1;60:90-5.

Zhang Y, Waterboer T, Pawlita M, Sugar E, Minkoff H, Cranston RD, et al. Human papillomavirus (HPV) 16 E6 seropositivity is elevated in subjects with oral HPV16 infection. Cancer Epidemiology. 2016 Aug 1;43:30-4.

D'Souza G, Wentz A, Kluz N, **Zhang Y**, Sugar E, Youngfellow RM, et al. Sex differences in risk factors and natural history of oral human papillomavirus infection. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2016 Feb 10;213(12):1893-6.

SELECTED PRESENTATIONS

Zhang Y, Waterboer T, Pawlita M, Burk R, Wiley D, Minkoff H, et al. HPV16 E6 seropositivity elevated in subjects with oral HPV16 infection. Poster at the 15th International Conference on Malignancies in AIDS and other Acquired Immunodeficiencies. 2015 Oct.

Zhang Y, Wilson TE, Adedimeji A, Merenstein D, Milam J, Cohen J, et al. The impact of illicit drug use on antiretroviral therapy (ART) adherence among HIV-infected women in the United States. Oral presentation at the 48th Annual Meeting of the Society for Epidemiologic Research. 2015 June.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Computer Skills: SAS (Certified Advanced Programmer for SAS 9), SAS SQL, STATA, R, Java, OCaml, Bash, Eclipse, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Office Access

Membership: Delta Omega Public Health Honor Society (2015-present), American Association for the Advancement of Science (2015-present), Society for Epidemiologic Research (2015-present), Chinese Public Health Forum (2014-present)

Languages: English and Mandarin

SELECTED COURSES

Epidemiology Methods, Statistical Methods, Analysis of Longitudinal Data, Multilevel Statistical Models, Survival Analysis, SAS Statistical Package, STATA Programming, Causal Inference, Public Health Surveillance, Programming Languages and Techniques I, Introduction to Microeconomics

SERVICES

Facilitator for Cancer Epidemiology, Prevention, and Control Journal Club, JHSPH	2020-2021
Departmental representative for the Student Assembly, JHSPH	2020-2021
JHU 2020 Planning Student Advisory Committee, Johns Hopkins University	2020-2021
President of Chinese Public Health Forum, JHSPH	2014-2015
Reviewer for Society of Epidemiologic Research Digital	2015